Guy Di Carlo, Jr. Civil War Research Papers, 1862-2002, n.d.
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Guy Di Carlo, Jr. Civil War Research Papers, 1862-2002, n.d.
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1995-015
18 boxes; 25.2 cu. ft.
The Guy Di Carlo, Jr., Civil War Research Papers consist of newsletters, newspapers clippings, photographs, newspapers articles, photocopies from published literature, maps, and calendars, related to American Civil War topics.
Guy Di Carlo, Jr.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The Guy Di Carlo, Jr. Civil War Research Papers were donated to Special Collections in April 1995. Addition materials were donated in 2003, 2004, 2006, and 2007.
Scope and Content
The Guy Di Carlo, Jr., Civil War Research Papers consist of newsletters, newspapers clippings, photographs, newspapers articles, photocopies from published literature, maps, and calendars, related to American Civil War topics. The collection also contains audio and videocassettes from Civil War events and television. Many of these are homemade.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged by subject matter. Note: Civil War Round Table is abbreviated as CWRT throughout the "Contents List."
Index Terms
Subjects:
Civil War; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865
Contents List
- 14th Brooklyn—"Red Legged Devils," Official Newsletter of the Brooklyn society. (Box-folder 1:1)
- Aeronautics in the Civil War, Official Newsletter of The Civil War Round Table of New York, Inc. (Box-folder 1:2)
- Alabama—Brochures, An Alabama Historical Association Essay, and relevant newspaper articles. (Box-folder 1:3)
- Alabama—Autobiographies of Stephen F. Nunnelee and Hiram S. Williams. (Box-folder 1:4)
- American Constitution. (Box-folder 1:5)
- American Revolution. (Box-folder 1:6)
- American West. (Box-folder 1:7)
- Americana—General. (Box-folder 1:8)
- Andrew's Raiders (James J. Andrews). (Box-folder 1:9)
- Annapolis. (Box-folder 1:10)
- Antietam, September 16-17, 1862. (Box-folder 1:11)
- Appomattox, March 29-April 9, 1865. (Box-folder 1:12)
- Arkansas. (Box-folder 1:13)
- Armies. (Box-folder 1:14)
- Army Division—Old Second. (Box-folder 1:15)
- Army of the Potomac—Battles fought. (Box-folder 1:16)
- Army of Northern Virginia. (Box-folder 1:17)
- Army of Tennessee—Battles. (Box-folder 1:18)
- Army of the Potomoc—Articles. (Box-folder 1:19)
- Art. (Box-folder 1:20)
- Atlanta Campaign—Kennesaw Mountain, Peachtree Creek, Atlanta (City) May 3-September 9, 1864. (Box-folder 1:21)
- Atlanta Campaign—Resaca, Cassville, New Hope Church. May 3-September 8, 1864. (Box-folder 1:22)
- Autographs. (Box-folder 1:23)
- Authors. (Box-folder 1:24)
- Bass, Henry—Newsletters. (Box-folder 1:25)
- Battlefield Houses. (Box-folder 1:26)
- Battlefield Preservation. (Box-folder 1:27)
- Battles—General Files (1 of 2). (Box-folder 1:28)
- Battles—General Files (2 of 2). (Box-folder 1:29)
- Beauregard, P.G.T. (Box-folder 1:30)
- Beauvoir—Last Home of Jefferson Davis. (Box-folder 2:1)
- Berdan's Sharpshooters. (Box-folder 2:2)
- Best of Virginia Country Magazine. (Box-folder 2:3)
- Bicentennial. (Box-folder 2:4)
- Biography of a Business. (Box-folder 2:5)
- Blue and Gray magazine. (Box-folder 2:6)
- Blue and Gray Television Series. (Box-folder 2:7)
- Book covers. (Box-folder 2:8)
- Booklets. (Box-folder 2:9)
- Booth, John Wilkes. (Box-folder 2:10)
- Bragg, General Braxton—Confederate Defeat. (Box-folder 2:11)
- Brice's Crossroads. (Box-folder 2:12)
- Brother vs. Brother article. (Box-folder 2:13)
- Brown, John. (Box-folder 2:14)
- Bull Run, July 21, 1861. (Box-folder 2:15)
- Burnside, General Ambrose E. (Box-folder 2:16)
- Bushwhackers. (Box-folder 2:17)
- Butler, General Benjamin F. (Box-folder 2:18)
- Butterfield, Daniel. (Box-folder 2:19)
- C.S. Navy—Miscellaneous. (Box-folder 2:20)
- C.S. Navy—Newspaper and magazine articles. (Box-folder 2:21)
- C.S.N. Admirals General File, Article on Rear Admiral B. Eiseman. (Box-folder 2:22)
- Civil War Round Table (CWRT) Congress, Manassas, Virginia, October 2-4, 1975. (Box-folder 2:23)
- Carroll, Anna Ella. (Box-folder 2:24)
- Casualties—Union and Confederate. (Box-folder 2:25)
- Cemeteries. (Box-folder 2:26)
- Centennial. (Box-folder 2:27)
- Centennial—100 years after. (Box-folder 2:28)
- Centennial—1861-1865. (Box-folder 2:29)
- Centennial—Commission. (Box-folder 2:30)
- Century Magazine Articles, 1881-1888. (Box-folder 2:31)
- Century Magazine—Battles and Leaders. (Box-folder 2:32)
- Chamberlain, Joshua. (Box-folder 2:33)
- Chancellorsville, Battle of, May 1-3, 1863. (Box-folder 2:34)
- Charleston, South Carolina. (Box-folder 2:35)
- Chattanooga, Battle of, November 23-25, 1863. (Box-folder 2:36)
- Chickamauga, Battle of, September 19-20, 1863. (Box-folder 2:37)
- Christmas. (Box-folder 2:38)
- Cleburne, General Patrick. (Box-folder 2:39)
- Clem, Johnny and Johnny Shiloh. (Box-folder 2:40)
- Colored troops. (Box-folder 2:41)
- Coloring books. (Box-folder 2:42)
- Combat. (Box-folder 2:43)
- Commercialism (1 of 2). (Box-folder 3:1)
- Commercialism (2 of 2). (Box-folder 3:2)
- Committee on the Conduct of the War. (Box-folder 3:3)
- Confederados of South America. (Box-folder 3:4)
- Confederate Calendars, 1986-1988. (Box-folder 3:5)
- Confederate Cavalry. (Box-folder 3:6)
- Confederate Government. (Box-folder 3:7)
- Confederate Governors. (Box-folder 3:8)
- Confederate Soldiers. (Box-folder 3:9)
- Confederate Generals (1 of 2). (Box-folder 3:10)
- Confederate Generals (2 of 2). (Box-folder 3:11)
- Confederate Veteran. (Box-folder 3:12)
- Confederate Veteran Indexes. (Box-folder 3:13)
- Confederacy—General File. (Box-folder 3:14)
- Connecticut. (Box-folder 3:15)
- Conscription and Recruiting. (Box-folder 3:16)
- Court Marshals. (Box-folder 3:17)
- Crime. (Box-folder 3:18)
- Crook, George—Union Calvary General. (Box-folder 3:19)
- Custer, General George A. (Box-folder 3:20)
- Civil War Round Table of Belgium. (Box-folder 3:21)
- Civil War Round Table of England. (Box-folder 3:22)
- Cyclorama. (Box-folder 3:23)
- Dana, Gustavus S. (Box-folder 3:24)
- Davis, Jefferson. (Box-folder 3:25)
- Delaware. (Box-folder 3:26)
- Delta Queen Riverboat. (Box-folder 3:27)
- Dennison, William—Governor of Ohio. (Box-folder 3:28)
- Desertions. (Box-folder 3:29)
- Draft. (Box-folder 3:30)
- Early, Jubal Anderson. (Box-folder 3:31)
- Edwin M. Stanton. (Box-folder 3:32)
- Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Box-folder 3:33)
- Elections/Inaugurations. (Box-folder 3:34)
- Equipment. (Box-folder 3:35)
- Ewell, Major General Richard Stoddert. (Box-folder 3:36)
- Farragut, Admiral David G. (Box-folder 3:37)
- Federal Blockade. (Box-folder 3:38)
- Finances—Confederate money. (Box-folder 3:39)
- Flags. (Box-folder 3:40)
- Florida. (Box-folder 3:41)
- Food and nutrition. (Box-folder 4:1)
- Foote, Shelby. (Box-folder 4:2)
- Foreigners in the Civil War. (Box-folder 4:3)
- Forrest, Nathan Bedford. (Box-folder 4:4)
- Fort Dickens, Pensacola, Florida. (Box-folder 4:5)
- Fort Donelson, Tennessee. (Box-folder 4:6)
- Fort Henry, Tennessee. (Box-folder 4:7)
- Fort Monroe, Virginia. (Box-folder 4:8)
- Fort Pillow. (Box-folder 4:9)
- Fort Pulaski, Georgia. (Box-folder 4:10)
- Fort Sumpter, South Carolina. (Box-folder 4:11)
- Fort Warren. (Box-folder 4:12)
- Forts—Union and Confederate. (Box-folder 4:13)
- Franklin, Tennessee, Battle of. (Box-folder 4:14)
- Fredericksburg, December 11-15, 1862. (Box-folder 4:15)
- Garfield, General James A. (Box-folder 4:16)
- Georgia. (Box-folder 4:17)
- Gettysburg, Battle of (1 of 3). (Box-folder 4:18)
- Gettysburg, Battle of (2 of 3). (Box-folder 4:19)
- Gettysburg, Battle of (3 of 3). (Box-folder 4:20)
- Gettysburg, Battle of—Articles from other CWRT newsletters. (Box-folder 4:21)
- Gettysburg, Battle of—Booklets, Pamphlets (1 of 2). (Box-folder 4:22)
- Gettysburg, Battle of—Booklets, Pamphlets (2 of 2). (Box-folder 4:23)
- Gettysburg, Battle of—Magazine articles. (Box-folder 4:24)
- Gettysburg, Battle of—Maps, Photos, Park Tour Maps. (Box-folder 4:25)
- Gettysburg, Battle of—Newspaper Articles. (Box-folder 4:26)
- Gettysburg, Battle of—Killer Angels, July 1-3, 1863. (Box-folder 5:1)
- Gettysburg Battlefield tower—Correspondence and Press. (Box-folder 5:2)
- Gettysburg, Field Trip—Cleveland CWRT, 1975. (Box-folder 5:3)
- Gettysburg—Peach Orchard. (Box-folder 5:4)
- Garibaldi, Giuseppe. (Box-folder 5:5)
- Glory, the movie. (Box-folder 5:6)
- Gone With the Wind, the movie. (Box-folder 5:7)
- Grand Army of the Republic. (Box-folder 5:8)
- Grand Review, May 23-24, 1865. (Box-folder 5:9)
- Grant, Ulysses S.—book reviews, magazine clippings, pamphlets, newspaper articles. (Box-folder 5:10)
- Grant, Ulysses S.—CWRT Newsletter. (Box-folder 5:11)
- Grant, Ulysses S.—Grant's Tomb (Ceremonies) (Box-folder 5:12)
- Grant, Ulysses S.—Magazine Articles (Box-folder 5:13)
- Grant, Ulysses S.—Miscellaneous. (Box-folder 5:14)
- Grant, Ulysses S.—Newspaper articles. (Box-folder 5:15)
- Grant, Ulysses S.—U.S. Grant Association. (Box-folder 5:16)
- Great Britain. (Box-folder 5:17)
- Greenfield Village. (Box-folder 5:18)
- Grenfel, George St. Leger. (Box-folder 5:19)
- Griersons Raid. (Box-folder 5:20)
- Guerrillas and Partisans. (Box-folder 5:21)
- Halleck, General Henry Wager. (Box-folder 5:22)
- Hampton Roads, Battle of. (Box-folder 5:23)
- Hampton's Great Beef Raid. (Box-folder 5:24)
- Hancock, Major General Winfield Scott. (Box-folder 5:25)
- Harper's Ferry, 1861-1865. (Box-folder 5:26)
- Hayes, Rutherford B. (Box-folder 5:27)
- Hays, Alexander. (Box-folder 5:28)
- Health and Sanitation. (Box-folder 5:29)
- Hildene—Robert Lincoln's Home. (Box-folder 5:30)
- Hill, General A. P. (Box-folder 5:31)
- Hill, Daniel Harvey—Life and Character. (Box-folder 5:32)
- Historical Societies. (Box-folder 5:33)
- Holly Springs, Mississippi. (Box-folder 5:34)
- Honorary Society of the Confederate States of America. (Box-folder 5:35)
- Hood, General John Bell. (Box-folder 5:36)
- Hooker, Major General Joseph. (Box-folder 5:37)
- Horses. (Box-folder 5:38)
- Howard, Oliver Otis. (Box-folder 5:39)
- Human Interest. (Box-folder 5:40)
- Humor & Cartoons. (Box-folder 5:41)
- Hunter, Major General David—Profile. (Box-folder 5:42)
- Illinois. (Box-folder 5:43)
- Index to Civil War Times—Volumes 15-24. (Box-folder 5:44)
- Indiana. (Box-folder 5:45)
- Indians. (Box-folder 5:46)
- Iowa. (Box-folder 5:47)
- Jackson, "Stonewall"—book reviews. (Box-folder 5:48)
- Jackson, "Stonewall"—booklets. (Box-folder 5:49)
- Jackson, "Stonewall"—calendar. (Box-folder 5:50)
- Jackson, "Stonewall"—CWRT newsletter articles. (Box-folder 5:51)
- Jackson, "Stonewall"—magazine articles. (Box-folder 6:1)
- Jackson, "Stonewall"—miscellaneous. (Box-folder 6:2)
- Jackson, "Stonewall"—book articles. (Box-folder 6:3)
- Jackson, Andrew. (Box-folder 6:4)
- Jaquess, Col James F.—First Mission. (Box-folder 6:5)
- Jaquess, Col James F.—Gilmore. (Box-folder 6:6)
- Jaquess, Col James F.—Horse soldiers. (Box-folder 6:7)
- Jaquess, Col James F.—MacMurray College. (Box-folder 6:8)
- Jaquess, Col James F.—Methodism. (Box-folder 6:9)
- Jaquess, Col James F.—Miscellaneous (1 of 2). (Box-folder 6:10)
- Jaquess, Col James F.—Miscellaneous (2 of 2). (Box-folder 6:11)
- Jaquess, Col James F.—Miscellaneous correspondence. (Box-folder 6:12)
- Jaquess, Col James F.—Peace missions. (Box-folder 6:13)
- Jaquess, Col James F.—Preacher regiment. (Box-folder 6:14)
- Jaquess, Col James F.—Secret Service. (Box-folder 6:15)
- Jews. (Box-folder 6:16)
- Johnson, Andrew—Impeachment. (Box-folder 6:17)
- Johnston, General Joseph E. (Box-folder 6:18)
- Joint Committee—Conduct of War. (Box-folder 6:19)
- Kearny, Major General Philip. (Box-folder 6:20)
- Kelly, Lt. Douglas O.—100th Ohio Volunteer Infantry. (Box-folder 6:21)
- Kennedy, John F. (Box-folder 6:22)
- Kentucky. (Box-folder 6:23)
- Kilpatrick, Judson—Union Calvary General. (Box-folder 6:24)
- Knoxville, Tennessee. (Box-folder 6:25)
- Laws/Constitution. (Box-folder 6:26)
- Lee, Robert E.—magazines. (Box-folder 6:27)
- Lee, Robert E.—miscellaneous (1 of 2). (Box-folder 6:28)
- Lee, Robert E.—miscellaneous (2 of 2). (Box-folder 6:29)
- Lee, Robert E.—newsletters. (Box-folder 6:30)
- Lee, Robert E.—newspapers and magazines. (Box-folder 6:31)
- Lee, Robert E.—Notes on Lee, Gray Fox, Burke Davis. (Box-folder 6:32)
- Lee-Jackson Memorial, Inc. (Box-folder 6:33)
- Less Than General Officers. (Box-folder 6:34)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Aircraft carrier. (Box-folder 6:35)
- Lincoln, Abraham—art. (Box-folder 6:36)
- Lincoln, Abraham—assassination (1 of 2). (Box-folder 6:37)
- Lincoln, Abraham—assassination (2 of 2). (Box-folder 6:38)
- Lincoln, Abraham—book covers. (Box-folder 6:39)
- Lincoln, Abraham—books and book reviews. (Box-folder 6:40)
- Lincoln, Abraham—cabinet. (Box-folder 6:41)
- Lincoln, Abraham—calendars. (Box-folder 6:42)
- Lincoln, Abraham—cartoons. (Box-folder 6:43)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Century magazine. (Box-folder 6:44)
- Lincoln, Abraham—chronology. (Box-folder 6:45)
- Lincoln, Abraham—coins and stamps. (Box-folder 6:46)
- Lincoln, Abraham—collectors and collections. (Box-folder 6:47)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Commander-in-chief. (Box-folder 6:48)
- Lincoln, Abraham—conspiracy. (Box-folder 6:49)
- Lincoln, Abraham—contemporary America (Box-folder 6:50)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Cooper Union speech. (Box-folder 6:51)
- Lincoln, Abraham—critics. (Box-folder 6:52)
- Lincoln, Abraham—death, train, and burial. (Box-folder 6:53)
- Lincoln, Abraham—"Did You Know." (Box-folder 7:1)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Emancipation Proclamation. (Box-folder 7:2)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Family. (Box-folder 7:3)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Food. (Box-folder 7:4)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Ford's Theatre. (Box-folder 7:5)
- Lincoln, Abraham—General files. (Box-folder 7:6)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Gettysburg. (Box-folder 7:7)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Gettysburg College. (Box-folder 7:8)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Health. (Box-folder 7:9)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Homes. (Box-folder 7:10)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Holidays. (Box-folder 7:11)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Humana. (Box-folder 7:12)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Humor. (Box-folder 7:13)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Illinois. (Box-folder 7:14)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Indians. (Box-folder 7:15)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Invention. (Box-folder 7:16)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Kentucky. (Box-folder 7:17)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Literature. (Box-folder 7:18)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Lore. (Box-folder 7:19)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Memorial in Redlands, California. (Box-folder 7:20)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Memorial in Washington, D.C. (Box-folder 7:21)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Memorial University. (Box-folder 7:22)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Miscellaneous. (Box-folder 7:23)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Movies and theatre. (Box-folder 7:24)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Mrs. Bixby. (Box-folder 7:25)
- Lincoln, Abraham—New Jersey. (Box-folder 7:26)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Newsletters. (Box-folder 7:27)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Observances. (Box-folder 7:28)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Ohio. (Box-folder 7:29)
- Lincoln, Abraham—On television. (Box-folder 7:30)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Ostendorf, Lloyd. (Box-folder 7:31)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Pennsylvania. (Box-folder 7:32)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Pictures. (Box-folder 7:33)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Policies (Wartime religion). (Box-folder 7:34)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Slavery. (Box-folder 7:35)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Societies. (Box-folder 7:36)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Symposiums. (Box-folder 7:37)
- Lincoln, Abraham—The Military and His Generals. (Box-folder 7:38)
- Lincoln, Abraham—Women. (Box-folder 7:39)
- Lincoln Times. (Box-folder 7:40)
- Lincolniana. (Box-folder 7:41)
- Literature. (Box-folder 7:42)
- Logan, John "Black Jack." (Box-folder 7:43)
- Logistics—Union and Confederate. (Box-folder 7:44)
- Longstreet, General James. (Box-folder 7:45)
- Loyal Legion (Mollus). (Box-folder 7:46)
- Maine. (Box-folder 7:47)
- Manassas General Management Plan. (Box-folder 7:48)
- Map—Campaigns of the Civil War. (Box-folder 7:49)
- Maps and charts. (Box-folder 7:50)
- Marine Corps. (Box-folder 7:51)
- Maryland. (Box-folder 7:52)
- Mason-Dixon Line. (Box-folder 7:53)
- Massachusetts. (Box-folder 7:54)
- McClellan, George B. (Box-folder 7:55)
- McCook's, The. (Box-folder 7:56)
- McDowell, The Battle of. (Box-folder 7:57)
- McDowell, Irvin. (Box-folder 7:58)
- McPherson, James B. (Box-folder 7:59)
- Meade, George. (Box-folder 7:60)
- Medal of Honor. (Box-folder 7:61)
- Medicine (Bickerdyke, Mary Ann). (Box-folder 7:62)
- Medicine and Surgery. (Box-folder 7:63)
- Meigs, Montgomery C. (Box-folder 8:1)
- Memorial Day (1 of 2). (Box-folder 8:2)
- Memorial Day (2 of 2). (Box-folder 8:3)
- Michigan. (Box-folder 8:4)
- Military. (Box-folder 8:5)
- Military engineers. (Box-folder 8:6)
- Military equipment (1 of 2). (Box-folder 8:7)
- Military equipment (2 of 2). (Box-folder 8:8)
- Military rank. (Box-folder 8:9)
- Milwaukee CWRT Newsletters, 1984-1986. (Box-folder 8:10)
- Minnesota. (Box-folder 8:11)
- Miscellaneous (1 of 3). (Box-folder 8:12)
- Miscellaneous (2 of 3). (Box-folder 8:13)
- Miscellaneous (3 of 3). (Box-folder 8:14)
- Miscellaneous Pamphlets. (Box-folder 8:15)
- Mississippi. (Box-folder 8:16)
- Mississippi—Historic sites. (Box-folder 8:17)
- Missouri. (Box-folder 8:18)
- Monitor and Merrimac, March 9, 1862. (Box-folder 8:19)
- Monocacy, Virginia, Battle of, July 8, 1864. (Box-folder 8:20)
- Morgan, John Hunt. (Box-folder 8:21)
- Mosby, John S. (Box-folder 8:22)
- Movies. (Box-folder 8:23)
- Music—Confederate. (Box-folder 8:24)
- Music—Federal. (Box-folder 8:25)
- Nashville, Battle of. (Box-folder 8:26)
- National Park Service. (Box-folder 8:27)
- New Hampshire. (Box-folder 8:28)
- New Jersey. (Box-folder 8:29)
- New Orleans, Battle of. (Box-folder 8:30)
- New York City (1 of 2). (Box-folder 8:31)
- New York City (2 of 2). (Box-folder 8:32)
- New York (1 of 2). (Box-folder 8:33)
- New York (2 of 2). (Box-folder 8:34)
- Newsletters—Mastheads. (Box-folder 8:35)
- Newspapers—Reporters, Photographers, Artists. (Box-folder 9:1)
- Nicknames. (Box-folder 9:2)
- Nixon, Richard S. (Box-folder 9:3)
- North Carolina. (Box-folder 9:4)
- Official Records. (Box-folder 9:5)
- Ohio. (Box-folder 9:6)
- Ohio—Articles. (Box-folder 9:7)
- Ohio—Books. (Box-folder 9:8)
- Ohio—Troops. (Box-folder 9:9)
- Ord, Otho Cresay. (Box-folder 9:10)
- Out West—Union and Confederate. (Box-folder 9:11)
- Parker, Eli. (Box-folder 9:12)
- Parks. (Box-folder 9:13)
- Paroles and exchanges. (Box-folder 9:14)
- PBS Civil War. (Box-folder 9:15)
- Pea ridge, March 6-8, 1862. (Box-folder 9:16)
- Pendleton, William H.—Chief of Lee's Artillery. (Box-folder 9:17)
- Pennsylvania. (Box-folder 9:18)
- Perryville, Kentucky, October 8, 1862. (Box-folder 9:19)
- Petersburg, Virginia (1 of 2). (Box-folder 9:20)
- Petersburg, Virginia (2 of 2). (Box-folder 9:21)
- Philately—Stamps and Covers. (Box-folder 9:22)
- Philately. (Box-folder 9:23)
- Phillipi, Battle of. (Box-folder 9:24)
- Photographs. (Box-folder 9:25)
- Photography. (Box-folder 9:26)
- Photography—articles. (Box-folder 9:27)
- Pickett, George. (Box-folder 9:28)
- Pleaston, Alfred—Union Calvary General. (Box-folder 9:29)
- Poetry. (Box-folder 9:30)
- Political/Elections (U.S. Presidents). (Box-folder 10:1)
- Politics (1 of 2). (Box-folder 10:2)
- Politics (2 of 2). (Box-folder 10:3)
- Politics—Southern. (Box-folder 10:4)
- Pope, John. (Box-folder 10:5)
- Popes. (Box-folder 10:6)
- Port Royal, South Carolina, Battle of, November 7, 1861. (Box-folder 10:7)
- Porter, Fitzjohn. (Box-folder 10:8)
- Postal History. (Box-folder 10:9)
- Prairie Grove, Arkansas, Battle of, December 7, 1862. (Box-folder 10:10)
- Presidents—General. (Box-folder 10:11)
- Presidents' Wives. (Box-folder 10:12)
- Quartermaster Department. (Box-folder 10:13)
- Railroads—Confederate. (Box-folder 10:14)
- Railroads—Union. (Box-folder 10:15)
- Reading list. (Box-folder 10:16)
- Reagan, Ronald. (Box-folder 10:17)
- Reconstruction. (Box-folder 10:18)
- Reenactments. (Box-folder 10:19)
- Reenactors. (Box-folder 10:20)
- Regiments—Maine. (Box-folder 10:21)
- Regiments—Mississippi. (Box-folder 10:22)
- Regiments—New Jersey. (Box-folder 10:23)
- Regiments—New York. (Box-folder 10:24)
- Regiments—Ohio. (Box-folder 10:25)
- Regiments—South Carolina. (Box-folder 10:26)
- Regiments—Pennsylvania. (Box-folder 10:27)
- Regiments—Wisconsin. (Box-folder 10:28)
- Religion. (Box-folder 10:29)
- Religion—Northern. (Box-folder 10:30)
- Reno, Jesse. (Box-folder 10:31)
- Richmond Campaigns—McClellan's Peninsula Campaign, 1861-1864. (Box-folder 10:32)
- Richmond Campaigns, 1861-1864. (Box-folder 10:33)
- Richmond, Virginia. (Box-folder 10:34)
- Richmond—Maps and Tourism Pamphlets. (Box-folder 10:35)
- Rivers in the Civil War. (Box-folder 10:36)
- Robertson, James I., Jr. (Box-folder 10:37)
- Rood, Hosea W.—Letters and Papers. October 1861-August 1965. (Box-folder 10:38)
- Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Box-folder 10:39)
- Rosecrans, William S. (Box-folder 10:40)
- Round tables (1 of 2). (Box-folder 10:41)
- Round tables (2 of 2). (Box-folder 10:42)
- Round tables—Australia (1 of 2). (Box-folder 10:43)
- Round tables—Australia (2 of 2). (Box-folder 10:44)
- Round tables—Cleveland, Ohio. (Box-folder 11:1)
- Round tables—Guy Di Carlo, Jr. (Box-folder 11:2)
- Round tables—Jackson, Mississippi. (Box-folder 11:3)
- Round tables—New York. (Box-folder 11:4)
- Round tables—Suffolk, Virginia. (Box-folder 11:5)
- Russell, Jerry. (Box-folder 11:6)
- Savannah, Georgia. (Box-folder 11:7)
- Schofield, John M. (Box-folder 11:8)
- Scott, Winfield. (Box-folder 11:9)
- Secession. (Box-folder 11:10)
- Second Bull Run, August 30, 1862. (Box-folder 11:11)
- Secret Societies—Copperheads. (Box-folder 11:12)
- Shaw, Robert Gould. (Box-folder 11:13)
- Shenandoah Valley Campaign, 1864. (Box-folder 11:14)
- Shenandoah Valley Campaigns, 1862-1864. (Box-folder 11:15)
- Sheridan, Phillip. (Box-folder 11:16)
- Sherman, William T. (Box-folder 11:17)
- Shiloh—Pittsburg Landing, April 6-7, 1862. (Box-folder 11:18)
- Sibley, Henry. (Box-folder 11:19)
- Sickles, Dan. (Box-folder 11:20)
- Siegel, Franz. (Box-folder 11:21)
- Sill, Joshua. (Box-folder 11:22)
- Slaves and Slavery. (Box-folder 11:23)
- Smith, E. Kirby. (Box-folder 11:24)
- Sousa. (Box-folder 11:25)
- South Carolina. (Box-folder 11:26)
- Southern Historical Society—papers. (Box-folder 11:27)
- Special reports and articles. (Box-folder 11:28)
- Spotsylvania, Battle of, May 8-21, 1864. (Box-folder 11:29)
- St. Albans, Vermont—Raid. (Box-folder 11:30)
- Statuary. (Box-folder 11:31)
- Statue of Liberty—100 year celebration. (Box-folder 11:32)
- Stevens, Thaddeus (U.S. Congressman). (Box-folder 11:33)
- Stone Mountain, Georgia—Atlanta Campaign, September 1864. (Box-folder 12:1)
- Stone River, Tennessee, and Murfreesboro, Tennessee, December 31, 1862-January 3, 1863. (Box-folder 12:2)
- Stoneman, George—Union Calvary General. (Box-folder 12:3)
- Stories about Lincoln. (Box-folder 12:4)
- Stuart, J.E.B. (Box-folder 12:5)
- Sultana. (Box-folder 12:6)
- Supplies—Union and Confederate. (Box-folder 12:7)
- Supreme Court. (Box-folder 12:8)
- Sutlers. (Box-folder 12:9)
- Tactics and Strategies. (Box-folder 12:10)
- Tennessee. (Box-folder 12:11)
- Texas. (Box-folder 12:12)
- Trent Affair. (Box-folder 12:13)
- Thomas, George H. (Box-folder 12:14)
- Tobacco—Food. (Box-folder 12:15)
- Transportation. (Box-folder 12:16)
- Truman, Harry S. (Box-folder 12:17)
- U.S Army Regulars. (Box-folder 12:18)
- U.S. Customs. (Box-folder 12:19)
- U.S. History. (Box-folder 12:20)
- U.S. Methods Balloons. (Box-folder 12:21)
- U.S. Navy—Miscellaneous. (Box-folder 12:22)
- U.S. Navy—Newsletters. (Box-folder 12:23)
- U.S. Navy—Newspaper and magazine articles. (Box-folder 12:24)
- U.S. Navy—Proceedings Magazine U.S. Naval Institutes. (Box-folder 12:25)
- U.S. Navy—The Cairo. (Box-folder 12:26)
- U.S.N. Admirals General File. (Box-folder 12:27)
- Uniforms. (Box-folder 12:28)
- Union Cavalry. (Box-folder 12:29)